<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <link href="http://arxiv.org/api/query?search_query%3D%26id_list%3D2308.03150v1%26start%3D0%26max_results%3D1" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
  <title type="html">ArXiv Query: search_query=&amp;id_list=2308.03150v1&amp;start=0&amp;max_results=1</title>
  <id>http://arxiv.org/api/CWQlMqYLJ7AmJfJlW4kPPR5CJBs</id>
  <updated>2025-02-25T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
  <opensearch:totalResults xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">1</opensearch:totalResults>
  <opensearch:startIndex xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">0</opensearch:startIndex>
  <opensearch:itemsPerPage xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">1</opensearch:itemsPerPage>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2308.03150v1</id>
    <updated>2023-08-06T15:56:12Z</updated>
    <published>2023-08-06T15:56:12Z</published>
    <title>"We care": Improving Code Mixed Speech Emotion Recognition in
  Customer-Care Conversations</title>
    <summary>  Speech Emotion Recognition (SER) is the task of identifying the emotion
expressed in a spoken utterance. Emotion recognition is essential in building
robust conversational agents in domains such as law, healthcare, education, and
customer support. Most of the studies published on SER use datasets created by
employing professional actors in a noise-free environment. In natural settings
such as a customer care conversation, the audio is often noisy with speakers
regularly switching between different languages as they see fit. We have worked
in collaboration with a leading unicorn in the Conversational AI sector to
develop Natural Speech Emotion Dataset (NSED). NSED is a natural code-mixed
speech emotion dataset where each utterance in a conversation is annotated with
emotion, sentiment, valence, arousal, and dominance (VAD) values. In this
paper, we show that by incorporating word-level VAD value we improve on the
task of SER by 2%, for negative emotions, over the baseline value for NSED.
High accuracy for negative emotion recognition is essential because customers
expressing negative opinions/views need to be pacified with urgency, lest
complaints and dissatisfaction snowball and get out of hand. Escalation of
negative opinions speedily is crucial for business interests. Our study then
can be utilized to develop conversational agents which are more polite and
empathetic in such situations.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>N V S Abhishek</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Pushpak Bhattacharyya</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2308.03150v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2308.03150v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.AI" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.AI" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
